achim.koh@gmail.com

https://scalarvectortensor.net

+1 (718) 413-0355

Koh, Achim [atchim] is a researcher, developer, translator and editor.

His work engages the technopolitics of machine learning, digital art, musical interfaces, and the South Korean web. His work has been exhibited at Seoul Museum of Art; he presented at the Theorizing the Web conference, and led multiple technical and non-technical workshops. Often multitasking while collaborating, he works in English, French, Korean, JavaScript, Python, and R.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2016-2018

Designer & Developer

Tools for Clear Speech, Baruch College, CUNY New York.

Produced new interface for website; designed and implemented web-based audio recorder and video player; implemented new identity.

2013-2014

Researcher

Making Lab, the 4th Anyang Public Art Project Anyang, South Korea.

Held a versatile position as local team lead for community makerspace including artist research, project management, public outreach, translation, editing, education programming. Part of the 4th APAP, the biggest public art Biennale in South Korea. Collaboration w/ Taeyoon Choi.

2010

Coordinator

BEHIVE Seoul, South Korea.

Played a versatile role including artist research, space management, onsite technical support, event organization, public relations for art gallery BEHIVE. Produced events including concerts by Joo Won Park, Trampoline, 404; live performances by Hang-jun Lee and Hojun Kim.

2009-2012

Co-creator, Producer, Head Writer & Audio Engineer

recandplay.net Seoul, South Korea.

Played a major role in a team setting from project conception, booking, public relations, writing, audio recording and editing. The project produced 50+ videos aggregating more than 5 million views. Engaged then-new technologies such as HD video streaming services and portable recording devices.

2007-ongoing

Translator & Interpreter

Written translations and oral interpretations to/from Korean, English, and French for commercial publications, articles, art exhibitions, technical projects, etc. 11+ years of experience.

Specializes in art and critical theory, digital technology, and music.

1 Achim Koh

SELECT SKILLS

Languages: Fluent in English, French, Korean, JavaScript, Python, R.

Machine Learning: Able to design and conduct experiments and complete workflows using scikit-learn and TensorFlow; able to build browser-based user interfaces using JavaScript.

Data Mining: Comfortable scraping, analyzing & visualizing data using REST APIs, headless browsers, scikit-learn and p5.js.

Web Development: Comfortable building static websites and/or work in frontend using HTML5, Jekyll and Git.

Creative Computing: Familiarity with audiovisual programming frameworks, including Processing, p5.js, Wekinator, Pure Data and openFrameworks. Knowledge of live coding platforms including Sonic Pi.

Audio Engineering: Multiyear experience in field and small studio recording, audio editing. Deep familiarity with Ableton Live and Audacity.

Physical Computing: Knowledge of electronics, Arduino, Raspberry Pi.

AWARDS & EXHIBITIONS

Research Grant (Third Grade). Open Net Research Paper Competition. "Zeroboard, Easy-to-install BBS —Rough sketch for a techno-cultural maker history of the Korean internet." Seoul, South Korea, 2016.

Korean Internet Tour Guide. SeMA Biennale Mediacity Seoul 2016. Seoul Museum of Art. Seoul, South Korea, 2016.

SELECT ARTICLES, TEACHING & TALKS

"Machine Learning: A Primer." Workshop. NYCDH Week 2017, New York.

(Translator/Editor) Kang, E Roon et al. **Seoul Libre Maps.** https://medium.com/seoul-libre-maps. 2017.

"Resources for a Critical Machine Learning." Presentation. CUNY IT Conference 2016, New York.

Koh, Achim, Kang, E Roon, & So, Wonyoung. "Zeroboard, Easy-to-install BBS—Rough sketch for a techno-cultural maker history of the Korean internet." Open Net Research Paper Competition, Seoul. 2016.

"Techno-culture Research Methods." Seminar. Seun Living Lab x Unmake Lab, Seoul.

"The Year 2015 in Korean Online Feminism: Two Movements Against Misogyny." Presentation.

Theorizing the Web 2016, New York.

"Simple music instrument with openFrameworks." Workshop. ITP Camp, New York, 2015.

"Maker Culture and Possibilities of Citizen Participation." Lecture. KAIST Creative Lab for Culture Technology Venturing, Seoul, 2013.

EDUCATION

In progress

M.A. in Liberal Studies—under advisement of Dr. Lev Manovich. The Graduate Center, CUNY, New York City.

Interactive Technology and Pedagogy certificate program

2015

The School for Poetic Computation, New York City.

2008

B.A. in Mass Communication. Yonsei University, Seoul.

2 Achim Koh